Trevor Farthing

Kirkland, WA 425.999.1328 • trevordfarthing@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE: Software Developer

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Software developer with two years of experience creating business solutions and product enhancements. Highly proficient using C#, C++, Java, and Python. Creative problem solver who works well alone or in a collaborative environment. Quick learner of new technologies. Results driven with the ability to look outside the box to find workable solutions.

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science, minor Math, Cum Laude, Gonzaga University, Spokane, WA, May 2018 GPA: 3.55

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2018-2020, *Software Developer,* C-Labs Corporation, Bellevue, WA 2016-2017 (summers), *Software Development Intern*, C-Labs Corporation, Bellevue, WA

- Designed, developed, and maintained plugins for IIoT (Industrial Internet of Things) platform.
- Investigated and helped address performance issues of Pub-Sub messaging system by developing scalable Docker-based test framework.
- Produced a new, customized way to record sensor historian data into an InfluxDB time-series database.
- Developed plugin utilizing Grafana to allow improved data visualization of sensor historians.
- Enhanced distributed storage system by implementing interface to store application data in SQL Server.
- Configured Azure Kubernetes cluster of Prometheus and Grafana pods to monitor cloud metrics.
- Created logger that extracts information from IIS failed request trace files and writes to system log.
- Extended and optimized local storage functionality by implementing an "append" option for JSON files.

2014-2016 Fundraising Caller, Gonzaga University Telefund, Spokane, WA

- Contacted hundreds of alumni and parents nightly to secure donations for the university.
- Contributed to fundraising over \$1 million for the university.

RELATED PROJECTS

- Created Vue.js frontend for cloud-based development environment and project management tool with senior design project team.
- Recorded, edited, mixed, and produced 8-song album over the course of a year. Proficient in Digital Audio Workstations and video editing software.
- Planned and proposed online Gonzaga radio station, which was carried out by university.
- Earned the Eagle Scout Rank with the Boy Scouts of America.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C#, Java, Python, C++, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Vue.js, Docker, Kubernetes, REST, Git